<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-27T12:48:46-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Thursday, November 26 2020</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-26.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thursday, November 26 2020" /><published>2020-11-26T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/entry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-26.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Journal,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good evening, everyone.  Or good morning.  Or good whatever time it is
on the planet I woke up on.  The nap I took this afternoon was
something so special, the best way I could describe it was
&lt;em&gt;otherworldly&lt;/em&gt;.  I had the whole upstairs bed to myself.  With our
room fan blowing wildly over my head, the gentle wind felt like a cool
cotton blanket draped over my face.  The shades were open, but when I
woke up the sun had gone down, and all the light had emptied out of
the room.  Had I slept for hours?  Decades?  Centuries?  Did I wake up
in another dimension?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before my nap, our small family sat down at the table for a humble
quarantine style Thanksgiving dinner.  We had spent all morning
finishing up the sides in the kitchen.  With the oven on full blast
all morning, I was already sweating through my nice outfit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why did you put on a nice outfit?” laughed Marissa.  My choice of
nice jeans, dress socks, and a button down shirt drew funny looks from
my pajama clad family.  Due to the lack of socialization today, even
baby Miles stuck to his more casual green dinosaur romper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I was just feeling excited about Thanksgiving,” I laughed.  “And I
really wanted to wear this shirt.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I wasn’t even sure why I dressed up for a holiday in
which we weren’t going anywhere or seeing anyone.  But my subconscious
intentions all became abundantly clear to me after dinner when I
changed right back into pajamas.  You know that glorious feeling when
you get home from a long trip or a big occasion and you first drop
your nice outfit to the floor?  I don’t think I’ve had that sensation
all year, and it could have been what truly catapulted me into the
most peaceful nap I’ve ever taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sip&lt;/em&gt;.  How was your Thanksgiving?  How many helpings?  How many
waves?  We’ve been chipping away at our mountain of leftovers all day.
Speaking of food, let me talk you through the spread we had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night I rinsed the turkey off in our sink and patted it dry with
a towel.  I would go on to season the bird and liberally apply
rosemary shallot butter underneath the loosened skin.  Inside, I
stuffed the bird with tied bunches of parsley, poultry herbs,
shallots, and lemon wedges.  Looking over my shoulder at a Martha
Stewart YouTube video, I tied the bird and slid it into the fridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a separate pair of wings, I made a simple turkey stock.  We put
the turkey stock in the gravy, and with a little bit of convincing I
corrupted Marissa into adding it to her Grandma’s stuffing recipe.
Meanwhile, Marissa twisted and turned around me in the kitchen like a
dancer, assembling sweet potato casserole, corn casserole, and
stuffing.  Marissa also baked a blueberry pie and an apple pie, and by
far her Sports Center highlight would have to be the impressive
crosshatch pattern on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s honestly kind of strange how well Marissa and I work around each
other in the kitchen.  We almost never bump into each other.  We never
get in each other’s way.  We barely use utensils the other person
needs.  Whatever mysterious natural instinct helps schools of fish
stay together in open water must also be what prevents us from
colliding into each other in the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Rodney spent the entire morning watching &lt;em&gt;Blaze&lt;/em&gt; on the
living room couch.  He casually shuffled into the dining room.
“What’s for lunch, Dada?” he said.  I imagine he was expecting a
peanut butter and jelly sandwich or a little bowl of mac n cheese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Take a look, dude,” I said, hoisting him up by his armpits.  His eyes
scanned the neatly stacked plates and spread of turkey, stuffing,
corn, green beans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wow!” he said.  “How did you make all this?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dude, what do you think we’ve been doing in here all morning?” I
laughed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I want &lt;em&gt;those&lt;/em&gt;,” said Rodney.  He pointed to a long plate of sliced
cranberry sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure thing, dude,” I said, collecting food on Rodney’s plate.  Per
his request, I flopped two whole slices of cranberry sauce on the
side.  Moments later, Rodney regretted his decision.  He slid his
plate back to Marissa.  There was a tiny nibble in one of the slices
of cranberry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t like these,” he said.  “These are &lt;em&gt;pretty gross&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marissa and I burst into laughter.  “What do they taste like?” I
asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They taste like… &lt;em&gt;spicy&lt;/em&gt; sauce,” said Rodney rubbing his chin
thoughtfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Rodney, I’m sure we’ve all had this seminal realization about
cranberry sauce.  I’m sure as kids we were all once lured in by its
shiny, wriggly beauty, thinking we were biting into a strange wedge of
homemade jello or a giant grape flavored fruit snack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They’re kind of weird thought, aren’t they?” I said to Marissa.  “It
really doesn’t make sense.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah you’re right,” said Marissa.  “I like them, but I don’t get it
either.  They’re cold.  They’re served just right out of the can.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We teased Rodney as we ate our food.  I kept the rest of the slices on
a plate beside Rodney.  “These are waiting for you when you’re done,
dude,” I said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moments ago, I put Rodney to bed.  He and Marissa stayed up past his
bedtime putting up Christmas lights.  It was too late for a bedtime
story, but I wanted to make sure we still got in our question time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Today was Thanksgiving,” I explained.  “It’s a day where we take time
to remember the things we’re thankful for.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“OK, OK,” said Rodney, nodding along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Like for example - I’m thankful for momma.  I’m thankful to have a
smart, cool son like you.  I’m thankful for how much baby Miles likes
to smile.  I’m thankful for two nice puppies.  What are you Thankful
for?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney sat up in bed.  “Open your mouth,” he instructed.  I sheepishly
opened my mouth.  Rodney extended his index finger and reached into my
jaw.  I felt his finger nail stab the very top of the roof of my
mouth, raking it back towards my gums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do you know what that is?” said Rodney, pulling his hand out of my
mouth.  He wiped his finger on my shirt sleeve.  “That’s your
&lt;em&gt;skeleton&lt;/em&gt;.  It’s inside of you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not thankful for that moment.  Someone else’s finger raking
against the roof of your mouth is among the worst sensations I’ve ever
felt.  But I am thankful to have a son like Rodney who never fails to
surprise me.  Even if I didn’t love with all of my heart, I would
still appreciate having him around just for his ability to surprise
me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’m thankful for you, reader.  At the time of writing this, I’m
over 458 straight days and 551 thousand words into this daily journal
project.  I’m touched by people like you who care enough to follow
along through good days and bad days, days where I feel depressed and
days where I feel hopeful.  Today I feel grateful.  If you haven’t
noticed, routines are important to me, and I guess at the core of it,
I’m honored to be part of your routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sending love from the Recker family.  Socially distant for now, but
never alone.  Have a happy Thanksgiving, everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dear Journal,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wednesday, November 25 2020</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-25.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wednesday, November 25 2020" /><published>2020-11-25T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/entry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-25.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Journal,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good morning, everybody.  Happy Wednesday, and welcome to what is
officially the day before Thanksgiving.  If your playbook looks
anything like mine, today is a great day to make herb butter, a green
bean salad, and some brown turkey stock from a pair of roasted wings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our friend Bob here is stuffed in a black garbage bag in my fridge.
Let me clear the air for any readers who missed yesterday, or for any
FBI agents that are doing their daily round-up of Internet wackos -
Bob is our turkey.  Like I said, Bob has been taking it easy all night
in an apple cider and herb flavored bath.  Yesterday while Marissa
fixed us evening drinks in the kitchen, I extracted Bob from his
plastic cocoon and rolled him into a black garbage bag.  Marissa
observed over my shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“At least he’s thawed this time,” I said as I crumpled the plastic up
and set it aside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do you remember two years ago when we needed to use pliers to get the
guts out?” Marissa laughed.  “That was such a struggle.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yet another example of frozen poultry biting me in the ass,” I
laughed.  “The more I think about it, I think maybe 95% of my cooking
hardships have stemmed from frozen birds.  It’s my bane.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, we hosted Thanksgiving for my family at our house.  We
didn’t give the turkey enough time to thaw, so when it was time to
tress it and set it up on the roasting pan, the solid block of ice
wedged in its cavity posed a problem.  Wearing our best occasion
clothes, Marissa and I would spend most of Thanksgiving morning
chipping away at the bag of frozen organs, like a pair of scientist
that just discovered a preserved cave man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slipped Bob into a black garbage bag.  Against our better judgment,
we went with our fancy metal ice bucket we use to serve cold drinks at
parties (do you remember parties?).  This morning, opening the fridge
to check on Bob, I saw a small puddle of red liquid.  I grabbed a roll
of paper towels off the counter, expecting the worst.  Mysteriously,
Bob’s tub only shed about an ounce of liquid, and cleaning it up was
trivial.  The garbage bag must have been punctured while transferring
it to the fridge, and perhaps the hole was plugged with a peppercorn
or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the turkey works out, I’ll have no choice but to incorporate the
accident into the official written instructions.  &lt;em&gt;Once the turkey is
submerged completely in brine, cut a small hole in the bag.  Allow the
raw juices to titrate into your cheese drawer throughout the night.
Do not clean your fridge.&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After cleaning up, Marissa and I continued to reminisce about the
Thanksgiving turkeys of past.  Last year, Marissa and I each made a
turkey for her side of the family.  The recipe Marissa was following
for her traditional baked bird instructed her to start with a hot oven
for the first half hour, then drop the temperature for the remaining
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2020-11-25-fridge.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;2020 11 25 fridge&quot; src=&quot;/images/2020-11-25-fridge.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our turkey Bob, tucked into his cozy, briney bed for the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Remember I forgot to turn the temperature down?” laughed Marissa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh yeah, your turkey speed run,” I laughed.  “We opened the oven at
like 11 AM, and we were like ‘yeah, that turkey finished cooking five
minutes ago’.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, outside on her parents’ front porch smoking my own bird on
my Weber grill, I was having the exact opposite problem.  I was too
conservative with the coal, and the biting Minnesota wind made it
difficult to keep the grill lit.  As Marissa’s flash cooked turkey
patiently waited on the table under wads of tinfoil, with only an hour
before dinner time my bird was still in what I call the &lt;em&gt;salmonella
zone&lt;/em&gt;.  It worked out in the end.  Marissa’s turkey was still warm,
and mine finished cooking just as we were setting the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sip&lt;/em&gt;.  Do you have some Thanksgiving turkey war stories of your own?
And how did your Tuesday go yesterday?  Rodney was positively jazzed
from the snow fall yesterday.  By the time I came downstairs for my
second coffee refill, he was standing in the kitchen putting on his
boots and snowpants.  Rodney waited impatiently for Marissa to affix
his puffy mittens, and with his hat barely on top of his head, he
rushed out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Poor guy,” laughed Marissa.  “It stopped snowing while we were eating
breakfast, and I think it’s even starting to rain.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He don’t care,” I said, taking a swig of coffee.  “Look at him, he’s
in heaven.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney wandered through the accumulated inch of wet snow in our yard
like he had just walked into Narnia.  Slipping on my flip-flops, I
stepped out onto the deck and formed a snowball.  I lobbed it at his
head.  Rodney turned around and grinned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch, I finished out the work day and joined Rodney in the
living room while Marissa cooked squash curry chicken for dinner.
Rodney hit his eating quota, and so for Rodney time we enjoyed the
newest Dude Perfect YouTube video before heading upstairs for a Zoom
call with the family.  My sister joined the call with her webcam
pointed at her new puppy, Henderson.  We showered the new member of
our family with embarrassing baby talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that was pretty much my Tuesday.  I’m happy to be hear at the end
of the work week.  Marissa and Rodney are on dessert baking duty all
day, and you can count on me opening a bottle of wine at quitting time
to ring in the Holiday weekend.  By a cruel twist of fate, the last
thing I have to do today is leading a remote training session for all
the new engineers we hired in the last month.  Say a prayer for the
poor souls that will be trapped in my power point presentation around
Zendesk’s high level architecture.  Trainee’s - don’t shoot the
messenger, but if you decide to mute me and look at something else on
your computer, I won’t take it personally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for stopping by today.  Hope you have a wonderful day today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dear Journal,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tuesday, November 24 2020</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-24.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tuesday, November 24 2020" /><published>2020-11-24T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/entry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-24.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Journal,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good morning, everyone.  Happy Tuesday.  Have you checked on your
turkey yet today?  Following our time table, today is officially the
first day of cooking something for the big day.  As of last night, our
family calendar is now speckled with orange blocks, each representing
something that needs to go in the fridge or on the oven.  If all goes
according to plan, today after work I’ll be heating up an apple cider
brine.  In the evening after it cools, I’ll plunge Bob into the
solution to let him enjoy his salty skin treatment overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to name our turkey Bob, by the way.  It may not be the most
creative name in the Recker family animal kingdom, but at least it
will serve as a nice identifying handle while I talk about prepping
for Thanksgiving this week.  Consider this my final warning - I’m
going to be talking about Thanksgiving &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with Thanksgiving plans getting going, I also have poop on the
mind - an unfortunate pairing, isn’t it?  Well past his fourth
birthday, we remain at the frustrating nexus of regular accidents and
occasional glimmers of hope.  While trying to read this morning, I let
the stinky distraction get the best of me, and minutes later I was
hunched over my phone reading Google results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now, Marissa and I must have already seen every google result.  We
know what’s out there and we’ve probably already tried it.  At this
point, I think googling the problem is just a form therapy.  Reddit
comments are particularly amusing.  For every “my child won’t poop in
the potty” thread out there, the only replies are people swooping in
with even worse stories.  Nobody is finding any answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It makes you wonder how much poop a person can take.  How much poop do
you have to clean up before it changes you?  Is there such thing as
&lt;em&gt;poop stockholm syndrome&lt;/em&gt;?  Can a person go &lt;em&gt;poop-mad&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While trudging up the stairs this morning, I saw Rodney’s bedroom
light switched on through his cracked door, and I heard him shuffling
his pillow and blankets around on the floor.  I peeked my head into
his room to greet him.  Rodney looked stunned at first, then smiled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How’s it going dude?” I said sleepily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Feels good,” said Rodney, spinning around with his hands on his hips.
“Are you going to shower now?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You bet, dude,” I smiled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“First, I have to show you something,” said Rodney expectantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“OK,” I laughed.  “What do you got?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have to show you something &lt;em&gt;on the floor&lt;/em&gt;,” he clarified.  My smile
faded.  In a panic, my eyes darted around his room.  His blanket was
balled up suspiciously at the foot of his bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Rodney…,” I said.  “Tell me what’s on the floor.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney danced over to his window, flinging his curtains to the side.
He gestured grandly at the window, directing my attention to a flurry
of wet, sticky snow flakes falling on the grass outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Snow!” he cheered.  “There’s &lt;em&gt;snow&lt;/em&gt; on the floor.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sip&lt;/em&gt;.  How are you dealing with all the poop in your life?  And more
importantly, how was your Monday?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was rough.  In the morning while grabbing a cereal bar, I
passed a stressed out Marissa at the computer anguishing over an email
opened up on the screen.  She shipped a painting to another country,
and it was lost in the mail.  The frustrated buyer informed her they
would be initiating a &lt;em&gt;chargeback&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;chargeback&lt;/em&gt; is the term for when a purchaser of goods goes to their
bank or credit card company directly to dispute the charge.  It’s a
perk meant to give people some last measure of confidence when buying
things on the Internet.  If a seller were to take my money, then
refuse to give me the thing I bought or give me my money back, as a
person I wouldn’t have much recourse.  But a bank or a credit card
company does, and after they’ve conducted their own investigation of
the disputed charge, they have the power to take their money back
despite what the seller thinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Marissa’s side, she’s working diligently with the post office.  The
post office can’t yet officially say the painting is lost, so they
can’t pay her the insurance.  She’s also relaying all the information
to the buyer, so they can relay it to their credit card company.  The
best case scenario is that the painting arrives before anyone’s money
returns.  But what if the painting is delivered after the chargeback
goes through?  I’d assume that the credit card company’s investigation
is supposed to prevent that from happening, but how do they make the
decision?  Since it’s their money and their customer’s line of credit,
don’t they already have a bias against the seller?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chargeback problem raises a lot of philosophical questions about
how things should be sold on the Internet.  Who takes the loss when
something gets lost in the mail?  According to ebay, it’s the seller.
According to Etsy, it’s the buyer (but they strongly recommend the
seller issues a refund).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marissa fired off an email and slumped back on her chair.  Almost
instantaneously, her phone buzzed with a text message.  “You gotta be
kidding me,” she sighed.  “Our debit card was stolen.”  Going along
with the theme of online money nonsense, Marissa would spend the final
hour of her quiet morning going over an itemized list of fraudulent
charges with an angry phone robot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To finish out our terrible Monday, Rodney couldn’t finish his dinner
in time for Rodney time.  It appears that Rodney’s distaste for mashed
potatoes slightly outweighs the enjoyment he gets from Rodney time.
After dinner I sent him to his room to think it over.  Not a great way
to end the day, I could have really used a game of Jenga to cheer
things up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kind of a tough day yesterday.  I was eager to get up this morning and
start fresh, and something as small as a little bit of snow on the
ground gives me hope that we might actually figure out some problems
today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for stopping by today.  Hope you have a great Tuesday,
everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dear Journal,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Monday, November 23 2020</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-23.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monday, November 23 2020" /><published>2020-11-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/entry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-23.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Journal,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good morning, everyone.  Happy Monday and welcome to the new work
week.  I don’t know about you, but for me work gets a little easier
around this time of the year.  The office gets a little quieter as
most people take time off.  Perhaps I would be a little more gung-ho
about using PTO in these last two months, but there’s not much work to
do anyway.  Throughout the holidays, we avoid pushing new code out,
and we avoid starting any big projects, so things kind of naturally
mellow out.  It’s a great time of the year to catch up computer
chores, like emails and software updates.  On top of everything, we
have a short week with the work week ending on Wednesday.  This might
be a socially busy time of the year for us, but at least I can look
forward to some down time in other areas of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sip&lt;/em&gt;.  How are the battle plans coming along for Thanksgiving dinner?
Currently, my top priority is cooking as much food as possible to make
more space in the fridge.  We have so much action happening in there
that I couldn’t even be bothered to save our mediocre leftovers from
last night’s dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which, linking to the last night’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/bFHe6hpoQGM&quot;&gt;Chicken Gaston Gerard&lt;/a&gt;
recipe, I caught a glimpse of the first video frame in which Chef
Stephane has all the ingredients laid out on his cutting board.  In
plane sight, his &lt;em&gt;mise en place&lt;/em&gt; included a cup and a half of heavy
cream, and all at once it dawned on me that I accidentally omitted a
major ingredient from the sauce.  It’s no wonder why I had so much
trouble getting the sauce to stay together - problems like that crop
up when you leave out small things like a cup and a half of cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Check it out,” said Marissa waving the leftover container.  “You
managed to make a little science exhibit, it’s like the layers of the
earth.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chicken I had stuffed into a tupperware container sat on three
distinct layers of congealed cheese, oil, and broth.  Later in the
night, I would flip it all right into the garbage can, letting the
mess slip into the bin like a melting, fatty chicken popsicle.  In the
coming weeks after we’ve exhausted Thanksgiving leftovers, I’ll have
to take another pass at the cheesy chicken recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, the big project of the week was the new desk we’re
installing in our bedroom.  To recap, we’re replacing my stubby little
floating desk with a longer rounded one that reaches all the way to
the end of the wall.  I’ll work in the same place, but I’ll have a
cozy “co-pilot” seat beside me, which will come in handy when Marissa
and I plan out the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney and I followed Marissa outside to retrieved the giant board
from our shed, wrestling it out of the rest of the clutter and setting
it on top of metal chairs.  Marissa diligently translated the
dimensions onto the board with a sharpie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2020-11-23-cutting.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;2020 11 23 cutting&quot; src=&quot;/images/2020-11-23-cutting.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Measuring out the new table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is the underside of the table,” she said handing us each a
Sharpie.  “So if you want, you cool dudes can doodle something.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney used his sharpie to add his own measurements to the table.
Between the two of us, I was the juvenile one that wrote &lt;em&gt;BLIPPI
SUCKS&lt;/em&gt; in permanent black ink.  With that, I exhausted my usefulness
to the team and went inside to make a round of hot chocolate while
Rodney and Marissa labored over the table.  Rodney followed Marissa
around with his plastic drill, his night vision goggles affixed to his
face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the weekend, Marissa would set up the carefully cut wood on
the deck to apply wood stain throughout the day.  The table, now
shimmering with a rich dark color, was starting to get us excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m really proud of this one,” said Marissa.  “I can’t wait to set it
up upstairs.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2020-11-23-stained.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;2020 11 23 stained&quot; src=&quot;/images/2020-11-23-stained.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new table, stained and waiting to be mounted on brackets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also spent some time this weekend attempting to play Twister.  We
got the idea after watching Rodney hop around on the rug in the play
corner, using colorful dots in the pattern as platforms in lava.
After picking up our own official copy from Target, we talked Rodney
into using up his after dinner Rodney time to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Left hand green,” said Marissa.  I groaned, bending over to plant my
hand on the mat.  Rodney stared blankly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh no, he doesn’t know left and right yet,” laughed Marissa.  “This
could be kind of difficult.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached over and tapped Rodney’s left hand.  “This one, dude,” I
said.  Rodney, acting like he was tracking with the game, smiled and
tapped me on my arm in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first game of Twister was a disaster, but things really got out of
hand when Rodney got a hold of the spinner.  He would march around
with it the rest of the evening begging me to play &lt;em&gt;spot on spot&lt;/em&gt; with
him while he called out imaginary commands from the &lt;em&gt;small wheel
unfortunate&lt;/em&gt; - all terms he coined from his own imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Twister sucks,” I said, walking back into the kitchen after putting
Rodney to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That was a hasty purchase,” said Marissa.  “I should have seen the
whole ‘left vs right’ problem coming.  Honestly we should have just
played hot lava on the rug.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“At least he likes the mat,” I laughed.  “He can incorporate it into a
pillow fort or something.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twister sucks.  To call it a “game”, I think is misleading.  It’s
about time we call Twister what it really is - a lazy, randomly
generated yoga routine over a crinkly mat in close proximity to each
other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for stopping by today.  Have a great Monday, everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dear Journal,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sunday, November 22 2020</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-22.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sunday, November 22 2020" /><published>2020-11-22T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/entry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-22.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Journal,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good evening, everyone! Hope your Sunday is going well.  Time to pour
a drink and cling to the last few precious hours of the weekend.  But
first, time to update the old blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of drinking, tonight’s beverage is a white wine I nabbed from
Hy-Vee while making our thoroughly premeditated Thanksgiving week
grocery run.  Our fourteen pound bird is safely nestled into his
temporary spot in the back of our fridge.  I spent pretty much the
whole afternoon cleaning out the fridge and cleaning vegetables for
the big day this week, leading right up to dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight’s dinner was an interesting French dish called &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/bFHe6hpoQGM&quot;&gt;Chicken Gaston
Gerard&lt;/a&gt;.  The recipe began with a whole chicken cut up into chunks. I
lightly browned the chicken in butter and oil over medium heat, then
shut the lid for forty minutes.  The cool part of the recipe was how
it cleverly utilized the &lt;em&gt;whole&lt;/em&gt; chicken - the carcass sits on the bottom
of the pot while the other pieces sweat out the juices, which get
turned into the most wild sauce you could ever imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blast the heat.  Add 100 grams of shredded gruyere to the boiling
chicken juices.  Add a whole glass of white wine, cream, and finally a
squirt of mustard before broiling it with cheese and bread crumbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being my first time with the dish, I had some execution problems.
Things started to go off the rails when I removed the lid from the
Dutch oven forty minutes later and discovered that my stove wasn’t
nearly hot enough.  I rushed the rest of the recipe, adding in the
cheese before the broth was hot enough.  A ball of rubbery grey
protein wadded up at the end of my whisk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look at this,” I said to Marissa, retrieving the mass from the pot.
“I think this is literally just cheese with all the fat taken out.  If
I didn’t know any better I would think it was just a piece of
chicken.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marissa tried to act amused, but the queasy look in her face betrayed
her.  “I don’t like it,” she said, quietly retching to herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I should have guessed you wouldn’t think that was cool.  I’ll go show
Rodney.”  Rodney took hold of the congealed mass and started to bounce
it on the kitchen table like a bouncy ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sip&lt;/em&gt;.  It’s been a great weekend.  The weather has been warm enough
to go for walks outside, and yet somehow also cold enough to enjoy hot
chocolate spiked with brandy.  Each of us is starting to show our
Christmas spirit in our own special way.  For Rodney, that means
bogarting our nightly story time to lead aimless, abstract discussions
about Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh I know,” said Rodney sitting up in bed.  “Let’s talk about
Christmas.”  I liked how he went through the trouble of acting like
Christmas just happened to pop into his head.  We both know Christmas
is always on his mind, and the more he can talk about it, the more he
can stave off his imminent bedtime.  On this particular night, I felt
like indulging him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“OK,” I said, taking a seat next to him on the bed.  “Tell me about
Christmas.  What do you got?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney leaned in like he was divulging a dangerous secret.  “Christmas
is coming soon,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I know dude,” I said.  “It’s like next month.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney shook his head.  “I show you,” he said, spinning on his butt to
face his pillow.  He planted his left hand down on the bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is our house,” he said.  Rodney turned and planted his other
hand on the bed on the other side of his pillow.  “And this is
Christmas.  It’s coming… &lt;em&gt;really slowly&lt;/em&gt;…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney began to draw his right hand closer to his left.  “And then
SUDDENLY, it’s here.”  His hands mere inches apart, he craned his neck
towards me to make sure I was tracking with the explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh I get it,” I said.  I raised my hands to match his.  “And then
when Christmas is here… &lt;em&gt;clap&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney looked horrified.  “No no no,” he scolded.  “It comes here.”
He spaced my hands apart.  “Christmas comes slowly and slowly until it
gets to our front yard, and then it stops.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I broke out in laughter.  All at once I realized what Rodney was
getting at.  To Rodney, the expression &lt;em&gt;Christmas is coming&lt;/em&gt; had
nothing to do with time.  To him, Christmas was a physical object that
was traveling to our house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It can’t &lt;em&gt;hit&lt;/em&gt; us, because our house would get &lt;em&gt;smooshed&lt;/em&gt;,” said
Rodney gravely.  “The walls would get &lt;em&gt;smooshed&lt;/em&gt;.  My toys would get
&lt;em&gt;smooshed&lt;/em&gt;.  Baby Miles would get &lt;em&gt;smooshed&lt;/em&gt;.  Everything!  Everything
would get &lt;em&gt;smooshed&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I got it,” I said.  “So Christmas is coming, but it’s just going to
stop in our front yard?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney finally nodded in approval, satisfied that his lesson had
finally stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to admit that Rodney’s understanding of Christmas captures an
imminence lost in the usual cliches.  Like Rodney, I think I prefer to
also think of Christmas as something barreling towards us.  It makes
me picture Santa sleigh careening through side streets, smashing
mailboxes and side swiping cars.  Indeed, Christmas is almost hear,
and you best pray that when it gets here it doesn’t &lt;em&gt;smoosh&lt;/em&gt; you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really related to that this weekend.  Sitting down at the computer
last night, I began to organize a TODO list around all the things I’d
like to do this holiday.  Thanksgiving dinner, Christmas cards,
Christmas presents, Secret Santa gift exchanges, virtual get
together’s, and most important of all, I have to begin my careful
curation process for my yearly hip-hop mixtape.  Things are about to
get serious.  This weekend has been like my last water break before
re-joining the race and powering through to the finish line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least the holidays are a good kind of busy, aren’t they?  It’s been
such a quiet year, and I’m in a place where I just feel like doing
things with people.  Even doing something as boring as standing in
line at Hy-Vee waiting for a register to open, I just felt so
stimulating to be around people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for stopping by today.  Have a great Sunday, everyone.  See ya
tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dear Journal,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Saturday, November 21 2020</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-21.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Saturday, November 21 2020" /><published>2020-11-21T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/entry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-21.html">&lt;p&gt;Last week I wrote an entry looking back at some stories from playing
drums.  A few days after I published this short essay, my phone buzzed
with a Facebook message.  The message from my best friend in high
school, Omar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just finished reading your stories about playing drums,” he writes.
“I’m a little offended you didn’t include our incredible (yet short
lived) drum line… for shame.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Omar wasn’t actually offended, of course.  After so many years of
being glued to the hip in high school, his sense of humor is still
unmistakable to me, even over text.  His light hearted chiding
inspired me to dedicate a whole story on its own to drumline, and if
Omar asks, we can just tell him that was the plan all along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that the CLA drumline was probably the coolest thing I
was ever involved in.  Nobody before us had ever done anything like
it.  We didn’t have any faculty help, and we didn’t start with any
money.  The idea to start the school’s very first organized drumline
was born out of our midday jam sessions in the band room.  Standing
over a dented snare drum clamped to a crooked stand, I was
demonstrating some of the new technical techniques I was exposed to in
the private lessons I was getting at church.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is a five stroke roll,” I explained.  “Two taps on the right,
two taps on the left, and then a final tap on the right.  &lt;em&gt;TAK-TAK
TAK-TAK TAK&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That doesn’t look too hard,” grinned Omar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, but watch,” I said.  “Watch how it sounds when you do it
faster.”  With careful precision, I quickened the pace.  My drumsticks
rattled on the snare drum, making an even, militant roll.  &lt;em&gt;TAK-TAK
TAK-TAK TAK-TAK TAK-TAK&lt;/em&gt;.  Without saying anything, Omar took out a
pair of drumsticks.  He clenched his jaw and tightened his grip.  His
sticks flashed on the snare drum.  &lt;em&gt;TAK TAK TAK TAK TAK TAK TAK TAK&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You see?” Omar smirked.  “I can make the exact same sound just going
left to right.  I don’t have the technique, but I have the &lt;em&gt;speed&lt;/em&gt;.”
He brought his sticks onto the drum again, playing the same beat in
double time.  His arms formed a blur in front of him.  &lt;em&gt;TAK TAK TAK
TAK TAK TAK TAK&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These midday competitive jam sessions in the band room gave us the
idea to start a new band in school.  I don’t remember who used the
term &lt;em&gt;drumline&lt;/em&gt; first, but we were immediately fixated on the idea.
Omar and I began to meet regularly to compose cadences and routines.
Neither of us had the know-how to make our own sheet music.  Instead,
we’d compose our music at night over the phone through beat boxing and
finger tapping.  I made a snare arrangement based off a song I heard
in one of the Halo video games.  Omar made several drumline
adaptations from his live DVD copied of &lt;em&gt;Stomp&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Blue Man Group&lt;/em&gt;,
which I was sure he had committed to memory.  We made drummified
versions of songs like “Carol of the Bells”, Switchfoot’s “Stars”, and
Ozzy Ozbourne’s “Crazy Train”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We handed out some fliers, announcing our first tryouts for the CLA
drumline.  Omar’s brother and my sister showed up out of obligation.
A few younger kids from the beginner band trickled in to the small
room attached to our school’s gymnasium.  Without enough practice pads
and drum sticks to go around, we handed out pens, chopsticks, and hard
cover text books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a guy on my church praise band who heard about our
blossoming drumline.  Being the band director at the much larger Lake
Zurich high school, he offered to gives us first dibs on some old
equipment they were phasing out - a set of marching band snares that
were short of some parts, and an old busted set of quad drums.  I
accepted his offer just in time for him to fish the quad drums out of
the high school dumpster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next school day, Omar followed me out to my car.  Together, we
wrestled the scuffed quad drums out of my trunk, then collected the
loose washers and screws that it had shed on the drive over.  Between
periods in the dark storage closet of the band room, Omar labored over
the broken quad drums.  At our next practice, Omar walked into the
empty gymnasium with the drums strapped to his chest, filling the room
with a thunderous drum fill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout our weekly practices, we formed a natural pecking order.
With his mighty quad drums, Omar led the line of bass and toms.  I
lead the snares, complementing the noise and energy with structure and
precision.  If one of our drumline members proved themselves worthy in
practice, we’d allow them to challenge someone else for their spot in
the line with a drum battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had our first gig at the annual CLA pep rally.  For fifteen
minutes, we’d be allowed to walk out into the center of the gym before
the entire school and play whatever we wanted.  We chose our best five
cadences.  We used old briefcase straps as makeshift harnesses.  We
had to tie down and duct tape the giant bass drum to Juan, who was
only in eight grade at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gym roared with applause as we marched out to the center of the
gym.  I remember hearing people scream so loud, I could barely hear
myself play.  It was clear that nobody cared that our drums weren’t
matching or that Omar and I were just shouting instructions to each
other.  The energy was palpable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the arrangements we played was a beat we called “Wipeout”,
based on the surf rock classic.  Apart from the rolling drum intro, it
shared little resemblance with the original.  We used the song as an
excuse to let our secret weapon Omar cut loose.  While my snares kept
a basic rhythm, Omar drilled the smallest tom as he approached the
front of the line.  I waved my stick, signaling the snares to drop
out.  Omar clenched his teeth, filling the silence with one of the
most spectacular drum solos I’ve ever seen.  Even though he was the
only one playing, he made it sound like there were six other musicians
accompanying him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first gig at the pep rally was an electric success.  Our
membership doubled.  We had more access to instruments and practice
spaces.  We kept the club going all throughout our senior year, making
appearances at basket ball games, holiday concerts, and the talent
show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the time to remember the humble origins of our high school
drumline made me realize how special of a friend Omar was.  I truly
miss having someone so energetic around.  Omar didn’t have an
apathetic bone in his body.  He was competitive, genuine, and had an
unquenchable passion for leaving a lasting impression on our tiny high
school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drumline was awesome.  Here’s all the clips I’ve managed to track
down.  Help yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PLhMFRzv8kTTBgmRxRg3WTpBrA47i5i9Wa&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last week I wrote an entry looking back at some stories from playing drums. A few days after I published this short essay, my phone buzzed with a Facebook message. The message from my best friend in high school, Omar.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Friday, November 20 2020</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-20.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Friday, November 20 2020" /><published>2020-11-20T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/entry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-20.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Journal,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good morning, everyone.  I’m pleased to report that today is in fact
Friday, and in only a short work day from now you are officially
relieved of duty.  Welcome to the weekend.  I’m looking forward to
this weekend.  I’m not on call.  We’re going to be doing some
Thanksgiving prep grocery shopping.  We’re hanging Christmas lights
around the yard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marissa and Rodney already got a jump on things yesterday.  They hung
sparkly white lights all around the backyard perimeter, taking
advantage of the beautiful day.  Apparently yesterday was in the
sixties.  Clicking through our google photos, I see that even baby
Miles got to hang outside in the backyard in his saucer, taking in the
beautiful weather.  Being the busy dummy that I am, I didn’t even make
time to step outside yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though we’ve already begun to hang Christmas lights, don’t worry.
We’re not going to break protocol.  Nothing is getting switched on
until after Thanksgiving.  I have however extended a personal grace
period for Christmas music.  I started listening to Chance the
Rapper’s Christmas mixtape over a week ago while I clean the kitchen,
just to prime the holiday pump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sip&lt;/em&gt;.  How was your Thursday?  Mine was socially stimulating.  I was
in an out of zoom calls with people all day.  In the morning I hung
out with Branden, teaming up to grade a take home assignment submitted
by a prospective intern.  We’d pick it back up again in the afternoon
just before my final meeting of the day to check in with our intern
Connor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So I read something scary,” began Connor.  “What is this ‘intern
review’ we’re doing?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Intern review?” I asked.  “I don’t know anything about that.”  Connor
smirked, and I sensed my genuine ignorance was just coming off as
cagey.  His eyes darted to another place on his screen, reading a
slack message aloud.  “&lt;em&gt;Want to pick up on this intern review?&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“OH that,” I laughed.  “Those are code screens for future interns.
You already went through all that, you’re done.”  We got to talking
about code reviews, and what exactly makes code good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If I’m being honest,” I explained.  “The most important thing to me
is that the code does what it’s supposed to do.  Most of the time I’m
reviewing code, I’m just testing it.  Afterwards I assess the way it
looks, but that doesn’t usually lead to any big discoveries.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It just sounds like you’ve been beaten down,” laughed Connor.
“Doesn’t there have to be some kind of standard?  What if the code is
just a mess?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I hear you,” I said.  “I pay more attention to how they got there.
If they were running their code often and being very disciplined about
changing one thing at a time, I like that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But this is a take home assignment,” reminded Connor.  “Remember,
they consider this &lt;em&gt;finished&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a good point, and it got me thinking about how my paradigm
for code review may need to adapt to grading a take home test.  I
can’t rely on &lt;em&gt;how they got there&lt;/em&gt; if I can only see the end product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connor went on to tell me some stories of what it’s like being a
computer science TA at the university.  How it feels when he’s handed
a mess of code and just asked to ‘fix it’, or what a struggle it is to
pull valuable lessons out of arcane sample code that has been buried
in the curriculum for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ve seen a lot of ugly code,” I laughed.  Perhaps there’s
something there that explains our different perspectives on code
quality.  I wonder if just a week of grading undergrad Computer
Science assignments would be enough to change my staunch &lt;em&gt;function
over form&lt;/em&gt; philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signing off for the day, I found my way into the dining room.  Marissa
was on the computer shopping around for eat out places to try.  We
settled on sushi from a cajun-japanese place near campus.  Cajun and
Japanese fusion might sound odd to some, but it’s actually not the
first time we’ve come across such a combination.  I’m pretty sure I’ve
already raved about our favorite cajun stir fry place in the mall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a knock.  I retrieved the tied plastic bag from our porch
through our cracked front door just as the delivery driver slipped
back into her car.  I set out the food at the table.  Marissa and I
divided up the sushi rolls, and on Rodney’s plate we arrange some
chicken tenders and a small pile of fries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tonight is a little different,” said Marissa.  “No timer, it’s just
eat out night and we’re trying something new.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How about this,” I interrupted.  “You have to eat just one sushi
roll.”  I reached across the table, gingerly setting a single piece of
caterpillar roll at the end of Rodney’s plate.  Rodney obediently
picked up the roll, nibbling off the side.  Rodney finished the roll
with the help of a few more gentle reminders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2020-11-20-sushi.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;2020 11 20 sushi&quot; src=&quot;/images/2020-11-20-sushi.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I told Rodney he was a good boy for finishing his sushi,” said
Marissa after he went to bed.  “He asked me to make sure that Santa
hears about it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I laughed.  “Of course,” I replied.  “He got lucky.  I already talked
to Santa, and it turns out that single piece of sushi was the deciding
factor for Christmas gifts this year.  The mighty pups tower was on
the line, and he made the big play when he had to.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we talked about Christmas presents, Marissa grabbed a magazine off
the kitchen table.  It was a Bed Bath and Beyond brochure.  “Speaking
of which,” said Marissa tossing the magazine onto my lap.  “Circle the
things you want, and put stars by things you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; want.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I smiled.  “I know the drill,” I said, thinking we were on the same
page.  But apparently I took it a little too seriously.  After packing
up the house for the night, I brought the magazine upstairs with me.
I crawled into bed with it and began to page through it.  After only
five minutes, I reached the end of the magazine, finding nothing to
circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So I was really disappointed, I didn’t find anything I actually
want,” I said as Marissa entered the bedroom.  Seeing me with the
magazine, she laughed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh no, I’m so sorry,” she said.  “I was joking.  I didn’t think you
would actually do it.  Their magazines are usually just the dumb
stuff.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah,” I whined.  “This is all just blankets, candles, bath
salts… I even brought a sharpie in bed with me.  All I circled was
this carving knife, and to be honest I think I was just reaching.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2020-11-20-magazine.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;2020 11 20 magazine&quot; src=&quot;/images/2020-11-20-magazine.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a letdown - my Christmas is practically ruined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for stopping by today.  Have a wonderful Friday today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dear Journal,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thursday, November 19 2020</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-19.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thursday, November 19 2020" /><published>2020-11-19T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/entry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-19.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Journal,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good morning, everyone.  Welcome to Thursday.  For me, this is the
point of the week where the mental gas tank starts to run low, and
feeling alert is a struggle.  I’m sure I didn’t help things by staying
up an extra half-hour last night hacking on a side project.  My tired
Thursday morning self wants to rebuke the careless, frivolous sleep
habits of my wayward Wednesday night self.  &lt;em&gt;You sacrificed a half
hour of precious sleep so you could dick around with a Makefile?  Was
it worth it, Alex?&lt;/em&gt;.  In a way, it was.  Even at the expense of
physical comfort, I’m sure it was nourishing me on a deeply
subconscious plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sip&lt;/em&gt;.  How’s the relationship between evening-you and morning-you?
Do you two work well together?  Do you look out for each other?  And
how was your Wednesday?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a full day yesterday between moving the chains on my security
work for this week, as well as training the interns on a tool I helped
write four years ago.  My enthusiastic, thoroughly memorized tutorial
echoed through the halls of our house yesterday.  After the session, I
found my way to the dining room to do some prep for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sounded like a lot of fun up there,” said Marissa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh it was fun,” I laughed.  “I’ve given that training so many times,
I feel like a club DJ, or like I’m leading a conga line on a cruise
ship.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funny comparison spurred me and Marissa to riff on what that would
sound like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gripped an imaginary microphone, pretending to be a low budget
DJ. “Aaaaalright everyone, let’s get ready to write - some
CLOUDFORMATION.  All hands on deck, grab your favorite editor and open
up a new YAML file.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just a reminder for passengers, make sure you turn your VPN on, or
you will not be able to proceed with the tutorial,” Marissa added
cheerily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our “moment of Zen” in the training session had to be when I was
explaining the uniqueness of stack names.  “Each stack name is unique
for the whole region,” I explained.  “So I’ll name mine
&lt;em&gt;cfn-training-alex&lt;/em&gt;, and you two should name your stacks something
similar.  I think using your name is a good idea.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connor and Ritik busily typed away at their computers.  I opened a
window to the AWS console and refreshed the list of CloudFormation
stacks.  Two new stacks appeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nice,” I said.  “Looks like that worked.  So we now have
&lt;em&gt;cfn-training-ritik&lt;/em&gt; and…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I squinted at my computer screen.  “And also &lt;em&gt;cfn-training-ritik-2&lt;/em&gt;.
Which one of you made that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connor slipped his hand up.  “That was me,” he said.  We broke out
into hearty laughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well the next step is copying the stack template into a new stack,” I
said.  “I was planning on naming mine &lt;em&gt;cfn-training-alex-2&lt;/em&gt;, but
because you were a smart ass now you’re going to have a naming problem
to solve.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After work, I found my way back down to an empty kitchen.  While
Marissa and Rodney busied themselves with their top secret Christmas
lights project, I started to prepare chicken.  Last night was an
important meal, you see.  It was &lt;em&gt;chicken redemption night&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may have been burned last week by a partially frozen chicken, but I
was prepared this time.  The bird had enough time in the fridge
thoroughly thaw.  Just after lunch I cut it up into quarters and left
them salted in the fridge to dry all afternoon.  I’d go on to sear the
pieces and finish them in the oven while making a pan sauce.  We
gathered around three plates of crispy chicken, garlic mashed
potatoes, and a french green bean salad.  For five minutes, no other
sound was heard at the table but chewing, swallowing, and the cracking
of chicken bones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So I’m realizing that I have a weird food impulse,” I said.  “I can’t
eat food without analyzing it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marissa looked up from her plate.  “What do you mean?” she asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I leaned back into my chair, wiping my mouth with a napkin.  “Even
though this version is a slam dunk compared to when I tried it last
week, my first thought digging into this was ‘I missed a few parsley
stems, the chicken needed to rest for at least another five minutes,
and I can taste the burnt pepper that should have been applied &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt;
searing it in the pan’.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marissa set down her fork.  She looked disturbed.  “Oh gosh, Is… is
that something you want to stop doing?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, not really,” I said.  “I think before I understood it, it has
gotten me into trouble.  But I think it’s also just how I enjoy food.
If you care about something, you want to make it as good as it
possibly can be.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just striving for excellence,” said Marissa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah,” I nodded.  “Anyway, just bringing up the realization in case
it comes across like I’m being overly negative.  I think I’m just
wired to look for things that could be optimized, no matter how
small.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No,” said Marissa.  “I appreciate the comments, I think you’re on to
something.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After putting the house away, Marissa found me in our bedroom at the
computer.  I was hacking on the same silly Makefile.  She slumped down
in the chair beside my desk, visibly frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I need help paying this credit card,” she said.  “I just don’t know
what to do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my main credit card, the one I got from our bank.  Recently,
BMO tried consolidating their old legacy credit card paying site with
their newer revamped online banking portal, and we had regrettably
slipped through the cracks.  The old credit card site we had
bookmarked just redirected to the new site, and the new site didn’t
reflect anything about our credit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s try online chatting,” I said.  “I think I’ve done that with
them before.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I clicked through to the support tab of the clunky website.  The chat
feature was taking down, alluding to staffing issues related COVID-19.
I grabbed my phone and dialed.  An automated voice greeted me and
began to drone, then music started to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve tried this one a bunch of times,” said Marissa.  “I wouldn’t
even bother, you’re going to be on hold forever.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It blows me away that a place like a bank can be so bad at collecting
their money.  Wouldn’t they want to make it as frictionless as
possible?  For crying out loud, even a loan shark would have sent one
of their street toughs to break my thumbs.  It would have been easier
that way, at least then I’d be able to explain the situation to a real
person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hung up and tried a different number.  A different voice greeted us
with some options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh this one is new,” said Marissa leaning in.  We both hovered over
the phone intensely.  Carefully navigating through the labyrinthine
voice menu options, Marissa and I felt like we were remotely disarming
a bomb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;BILL PAYMENT&lt;/em&gt;,” read the voice.  Marissa’s eyes bulged out of her
head.  “OH!  You found it.  CRAP, they’re going to ask for the routing
number,” she said, scrambling to look it up on her phone.  I snapped
my fingers, wildly pointing at my computer screen.  “Just use my
laptop, we can log in here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;To agree to the terms of services and submit the payment, press 1&lt;/em&gt;,”
droned the voice.  Holding my phone with both hands, I mashed the
button.  “&lt;em&gt;Payment complete&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marissa sighed, sinking further into her chair.  “Thank you so much,”
she said.  “That bill was due today.  I was afraid I’d have to go in
to the branch or something.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for stopping by today.  Have a wonderful day today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dear Journal,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wednesday, November 18 2020</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-18.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wednesday, November 18 2020" /><published>2020-11-18T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/entry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-18.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Journal,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good morning, everyone.  Happy Wednesday.  Welcome to the middle of
the work week, rounding second base, the half mile marker.  At the
moment, I’m sitting down in a chair, and I just have to take a minute
to tell you how wonderful it feels to sit.  Last night after putting
the kids to bed, finishing our chores, and putting the house away,
Marissa and I sank into our usual seats on the couch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know if I’m getting old, or something,” she said, carefully
lifting her chilled gin and tonic off the coffee table, “but it just
feels so good to sit down.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh I hear that,” I said.  My glass beer bottle quietly clinked on the
coffee table as I set it down.  “So in the mornings, after I finish
cleaning up, feeding the starter, and brewing coffee, I sit down for
exactly a half hour in that chair to read, and it feels so good it’s
like my whole body starts to sing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When you sit down, do you feel like you’re getting a back massage?”
she asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh you have no idea,” I laughed.  “My back literally cracks.  It
feels so good I think I could cry, or just immediately fall asleep.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, let’s respect the simple joy of sitting down.  The physical
act, along with what sitting down symbolizes.  No more jobs, and I’m
not planning on going anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sip&lt;/em&gt;.  How do you feel about sitting down?  Do you seek it out, or do
you actively avoid it?  Are you one of these thrill-seeking standing
desk people I keep hearing about?  Maybe you’re one of those weirdos
that like to shuffle on a treadmill while you work.  Not me and my
butt, I’ll take a good chair every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was a good day - not for work, but for everything else
around it.  Remember that annoying secret task I was complaining about
yesterday?  I had ambitions of taking care of it in its entirety with
one focused afternoon blitz.  I shut off slack.  I closed our bedroom
door.  I got close, but I wasn’t quite able to put it to rest.  As is
true of most annoying tasks, it gave birth to a gaggle of smaller
annoying tasks, and mistaking me for the head of their annoying task
family unit, these new little baby annoying tasks continue to waddle
behind me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I have a right to complain, I have to be mindful of
letting the negativity affect the team.  During our morning stand-up
update, I jokingly referred to the chore as &lt;em&gt;eating a shit sandwich&lt;/em&gt;.
But I wasn’t careful with my wording, and I made it sound like both
the security chore &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; working with the interns were all part of the
shit sandwich.  “Just to be clear, I didn’t mean to lump our new
intern project in with the drudgery of this chore, I’m actually really
looking forward to getting into this together,” I clarified later over
slack.  I’m half certain that nobody in the call made that conclusion,
but you have to be careful with your words in a remote working
environment.  With nothing holding people together except for zoom
calls, slack messages, and google docs, the importance of precise
wording can’t be understated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, Marissa floated the idea of taking a family walk.
We needed to pick up some meds from the neighborhood vet, and Marissa
thought the weather was nice enough to finally take the whole family
to her new secret running spot by the lake.  Feeling the need to vent,
I jumped on the offer, and so we bundled up and headed out deeper into
our neighborhood.  For the first few blocks, I filled Marissa’s ear
with complaining.  But then Rodney shook me out of my bad head space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look at these rocks!” yelled Rodney, running ahead of the back.  “Oh,
a person!  Hi person!  Look at their cute puppy, what a nice boy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rodney was so enraptured with the scenery that he distracted me from
my work rant, stopping at every stick lying in the middle of the
sidewalk and every pile of leaves at the end of driveways to marvel at
their beauty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He hasn’t been out in a really long time,” said Marissa.  Rodney
continued to bounce around like a hummingbird in the spring.  He
stopped in his tracks to gaze at an airplane overhead scraping the
clear blue sky.  He leaped over a concrete stair.  He leaned in to
pluck a crabapple off of a neighbor’s tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2020-11-18-airplane.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;2020 11 18 airplane&quot; src=&quot;/images/2020-11-18-airplane.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t fall in the sewer,” he said turning around to warn me.  “The
&lt;em&gt;enn-jin&lt;/em&gt; turtles live down there, pretty scary.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought about what this quarantine has been like for Rodney.  Rodney
doesn’t know the term COVID or quarantine.  He just knows that people
are getting sick and we’re waiting for them to get better.  He doesn’t
understand the context of why we can’t go anywhere and why it’s taking
so long to stop it.  A walk down a new side street and a few minutes
by a chilly lake was all it took for his heart to burst with joy.  He
didn’t let a single person pass us on the sidewalk across the street
without asking them at least four questions.  He sprinted down each
stretch of sidewalk like a relay runner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We grabbed a seat on a wooden bench by the water.  Rodney ripped off
his winter jacket and hat and climbed down to the water.  I helped him
lean forward far enough to feel the chilly water on his fingers.
“It’s so beautiful,” he said, trying to taste it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When quarantine is done, I’m taking that kid to Dave and Buster’s
every day for a week,” I laughed.  Marissa and I, both misty eyed from
watching Rodney fling sticks into the lake, packed up our things and
walked home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at home, we made hot chocolate.  Marissa used her blowtorch to
toast the marshmallows on top.  Rodney, out of breath from his
afternoon eventful afternoon walk, disappeared into his room with his
own full mug of hot chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what I got today.  Thanks for stopping by, reader.  Have a
great day today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(bonus content)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2020-11-18-baby.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;2020 11 18 baby&quot; src=&quot;/images/2020-11-18-baby.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah, Miles was there too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dear Journal,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tuesday, November 17 2020</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-17.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tuesday, November 17 2020" /><published>2020-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/entry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2020-11-17.html">&lt;p&gt;This journal entry is dedicated to the memory of Stephane II, the bold
and beautiful cleaner shrimp that recently moved into our tank.  This
morning I found Stephane on his back against the lonely faux ocean
floor, his legs curled into his body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With shrimp, there’s always a chance they’ll spring to life when you
least expect it.  But the twenty four hour clock starts now, and
readers, it’s not looking good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it’s just a shrimp, but this one hurts on a different level.
He was strong - in only a half of a day, he nursed himself back to
health from the pale, weak creature he was when he arrived on our
doorstep.  Stephane was a character, making a splash on his first day
in the tank by putting the bigger clown fish Obb in her place,
brandishing his scary shrimp hands like swords and strafing around the
tank floor with his chest out.  Stephane was endlessly curious and
fearless to a fault.  After only the third day, he felt comfortable
enough to crawl along Marissa’s hand to scoop of a shrimp flake before
leaping back into the deep like an alien.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the shrimp hospital, I guess.  They’re really going to have to
do a number on him this time.  Sorry, Rodney.  The specially trained
shrimp doctors we have on retainer will have to keep Stephane
suspended in one of those healing tanks from Star Wars for several
months.  They might even have to bring in a shrimp priest and a shrimp
shaman to take a look.  Of course I have no idea what actually
happened - the tedious and illusive saltwater autopsy rests on
Marissa’s shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning, seeing Stephane lying on his back in the bottom of the
tank kind of reminded me the way Nick Foles looked at the end of last
night’s Bears game.  Marissa and I watched on in horror as medical
aides encircled him.  The game camera passed overhead to capture the
full depressing moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just imagine your Nick Foles right now and you see that little camera
on a string pass over the top of you,” said Marissa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nervously standing in the middle of the living room, I shook my head.
“I don’t think anyone from this offense is coming back this year,” I
said.  “Hopefully it’s just a full rebuild.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To loosely quote &lt;em&gt;Silver Linings Playbook&lt;/em&gt;, we’ve got some bad juju in
this house between the Bears getting embarrassed and our shrimp dying.
Just as Robert Deniro’s character says, &lt;em&gt;we gotta fix the juju and get
some good juju goin’&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sip&lt;/em&gt;.  On a more sincere level, it’s been a real struggle staying
positive through quarantine heading into the holidays.  For obvious
reasons, we’re not traveling anywhere or seeing anyone.  For the first
time in our family’s history we’re spending both Thanksgiving and
Christmas alone.  Yesterday I took a coffee break, and Marissa and I
discussed the hard truth of the coming holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It makes me really sad,” said Marissa.  “I get a knot in my throat
whenever a Christmas song comes on in the radio.  I think I’m coping
with it by going all out for decorations.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She gestured to a stack of newly purchased Christmas lights - eight
boxes of white lights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s OK,” I said.  “So go all out for decorations.  If that helps
you, then it helps you.  It sucks that we can’t see family, but we
have a chance to make this holiday memorable in its own way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to see my own Silver Lining in quarantine, there’s a good
chance that we may never have a Thanksgiving and a Christmas like 2020
ever again.  We have chance to make it special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Put out all the lights you want,” I laughed.  “Put one of those giant
inflatable Santas in our yard.  At this point I could care less, just
have fun.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s actually going to be a snow globe,” said Marissa.  “A giant
inflatable snow globe with inflatable Santas inside of it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case it’s not obvious, we’re not serious about the inflatable
decorations.  Maybe if we’re somehow still in quarantine by Christmas
2021, we’ll consider it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just trying to stay positive, and things could be worse.  Work is
keeping me busy.  This week, I just found out that I have until Friday
to do something very tedious and repetitive.  The work relates to a
troubling security finding, so as much as I’d love to dazzle you with
the gory details, it’s a secret.  On top of the security thing, I’m
trying to find time to work with our team’s interns, and slowly
chipping away at moving work items over from my old team.  To sum up,
this week there are lots of buttons to be clicked, spreadsheets to be
filled, and text fields that need to be copied from one form field to
another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the plus side, I mistakingly read way too much of my book for book
club yesterday.  Missing the fact I was only supposed to read Chapter
1, I powered through Part 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a fascinating discussion about the book, led by my teammate
Fong.  The book is all about how Toyota’s production model was applied
to writing software, and how that simple association brought about a
revolution in the world of making software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s always fun hearing what students think of idioms like “small
batch size”, “short lead time”, and “highly visible work”.  To a young
person in school right now, this is all common sense - break up the
work into smaller chunks, focus on one small change at a time, and
work in a way where everyone can see what you’re doing.  The book
illuminates a time in which these things weren’t common sense, and
people built websites like they were building a spaceship.  Nobody
writes any code until the design is finalized.  Months of development
and testing leading up to a single launch day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Free discussion, does anyone else have any other thoughts?” said
Fong.  A hush fell over the zoom room.  I wheeled my chair over to our
project wall, plucking an index card off the whiteboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have something dorky to show off,” I said leaning into my
microphone.  “My wife and I use the system to get work done around the
house.  This is a card for painting the crown molding in our baby’s
room.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what I got today.  As some bonus content, take a look at the
weird makeshift toy hospital happening in our kitchen right now.
Ryder suffered a freak accident that left his butt severed from the
rest of his body.  We spent the night lying face down, waiting for the
glue to dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2020-11-17-ryder.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;2020 11 17 ryder&quot; src=&quot;/images/2020-11-17-ryder.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grizzly, yes.  But nothing compared to what the poop prize rubber
t-rex has been through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2020-11-17-dino.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;2020 11 17 dino&quot; src=&quot;/images/2020-11-17-dino.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His tail was ripped off, and he lost a lot of gooey beads in the
process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for stopping by today.  Have a great Tuesday everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This journal entry is dedicated to the memory of Stephane II, the bold and beautiful cleaner shrimp that recently moved into our tank. This morning I found Stephane on his back against the lonely faux ocean floor, his legs curled into his body.</summary></entry></feed>